Ryan D. McCauley

Software Developer (Full Stack)

rmccauley01@gmail.com ryan-mccauley.com

2738 Tortuga Verde

(405) 888-0316

San Antonio, Tx 78245

Possess not only a wide breadth of experience including full stack web development, machine learning, and Power Automate; but also, the soft skills needed to work on teams attained through college athletics and personal business ventures.

WORK EXPERIENCE

HPE, Remote — *Software Developer*

May 2022 - Current

Produced an application enabling customers to see, manipulate, and analyze code coverage data. Technologies: python, vue.js, and SQL.

J.B. Hunt, Fayetteville AR — Software Developer

May 2021 - August 2021

Built a Power Automate flow to automate load board bidding that freed up man hours and significantly increased task efficiency.

Texas A&M University, College Station TX — Teaching Assistant

August 2020 - December 2020

Assisted a professor in teaching Python to Freshman engineering students. Hosted office hours and lab hours to teach basic coding and Python concepts.

SKILLS

Technical Skills: C++, Java, C#, Python, Haskell, TensorFlow, SQL, No SQL, SQL Server, JavaScript, Vue.js, CSS, HTML, Power Automate, Cloud (Microsoft Azure and Google Firebase).

Additional Skills: Accomplished Public Speaker, Strong Leader, and Motivator

EDUCATION

Texas A&M University, College Station — Bachelor of Science – *Computer Science GPA*: 3.65 on a 4.0 scale. *Graduate May* 2023

College Activities: Texas A&M Engineering Honors Program, Engineers Without Borders, Texas A&M Rugby Club

Recognition: Deans Honor Roll Spring 2020, Engineering Distinguished Student Award Fall 2020, Deans Honor Roll Spring 2021

ENTREPRENEURSHIP

Castaway Apparel — Former Owner and Operator

July 2021 - November 2021

Built and managed website, sales funnel, and marketing campaigns. Run social media accounts as well as create advertisements.

McCauley Brothers Mowing — *Former Owner and Operator*

March 2020 - August 2021

Oversaw 30 lawns, managed four employees, ran marketing, and handled all interactions with customers.

CODING PROJECTS

Coverage Data Analytics Application — *HPE*

May 2022 - Current

Project that allows customers to access previously unutilized coverage data. The application provides analytics components that allow users to better comprehend the data as well as tools allowing for the manipulation and exporting of the data.

Business Impact: Directly used by dozens of employees across the Coverage group at HPE, this application will reduce man hours and make testing more efficient.

Skills Utilized: Full stack web development, SQL, data analytics (Plotly), and python coding.

Power Automate Manual Process Automation — JB Hunt

May 2021 - August 2021

Project where a flow was created to automate a previously manual process by accessing a website, scraping multiple webpages, sending information to a pricing program, then automatically bidding. The flow needed to be general enough to deal with dozens of different company webpages while still being robust enough to gather all the required information.

Business Impact: Allowed for the reduction of man hours across the entire load board bidding space. Reducing the required manual work from 3 hours per day to roughly 15 minutes per employee.

Skills Utilized: Power Automate flow, front end web development.

Machine Learning Projects — CSCE 421, Texas A&M University

January 2022 - May 2022

CSCE 421 (Machine Learning) covered a wide array of machine learning principles, concepts, research, and tools. The culmination of this learning can be seen in the following four programming assignments which were all completed using a combination of Python and TensorFlow.

Project Assignment 1: Covered supervised learning, perceptron units, gradient descent, and backpropagation.

More Information: https://colab.research.google.com/drive/1JnmP44SDN5Yk26tMEBrewRNiW79clFAq?usp=sharing

Project Assignment 2: Covered deterministic state machines, Q-learning, and SARSA

More Information: https://colab.research.google.com/drive/1FETfuY9M4wgL6_UaX8kIkMAMINtj82JV?usp=sharing

Project Assignment 3: Covered entropy and decision tree learning.

More Information: https://colab.research.google.com/drive/1IPnmOlawCFbfYr8G3sRUUK477Yow73IA?usp=sharing

Project Assignment 4: Covered dimensionality reduction, conditional independence, Naïve Bayes Classifier, and local methods.

More Information: https://colab.research.google.com/drive/1NMa_h3E4MdjBJoekagC4qHm-IYyw7vQf?usp=sharing

Language Parser Creation (Haskell) — CSCE 314, Texas A&M University

May 2021 - August 2021

Project that created a parser for a language created by Professor Shell called "W" that focuses on allowing users to efficiently write mathematical statements. After parsing it then runs the program in Haskell.

Skills Utilized: Haskell, functional programming, and understanding the complexity of code execution.

More Information: Rmccauley01/WParser (github.com)